I've covered some queries as part of my previous course, the comprehensive Esquibel course, but I'll
give a quick refresher on some queries.
The focus of this section really is on common table expressions.
A subquery is a query that is nested inside of another query, a sub query can occur anywhere and expression
is allowed, such as the select clause, the front clause, the where clause, the having clause and
so on.
Sub queries must be enclosed in parenthesis.
So normally some queries are executed before the hour to query if you have multiple sub queries nested
inside each other, then the innermost sub query is evaluated first and then the next sub query and
finally the output query.
A scalar sub subquery is one where the sub query returns only one expression, forming one column and
one row.
You can use KAILASAM queries in most places that you can use and also query the below list shows where
you can't use Gayler sub queries.
OK, now let's do some examples first, let's query the AMP table.
OK.
Now I want to return a sub query that will always select employees that are earning above the average
salary.
So to find the average salary, I can type select average salary from.
And this is the average salary, I can then use this as a subquery in the workforce as such.
And then enclose this in parenthesis as a sub query.
So if I format this.
It's.
The innermost subquery will execute first, returning this No.
Then the outer query will execute for when the salary is greater than two thousand and seventy three.
This is also known as a scale sub query as it only returns one value in the sub query.
Now, if I had run.
We return all salaries above the average.
You can also use a sub query in the front rows, so if I type select any cell from select store from
where you name equals King.
I essentially have a sub query after the from clause.
When you have a submarine in the front rows, it's referred to as an inline V.
Now, let's return all the employees where the employees are in Department 10.
I can first find out the employee numbers of all employees in Department Ten by typing select employee
from where Depner equals 10.
I can now use this as a subquery.
And use the inclose.
To select all employees where the employee number is in this list like this.
And Deborah.
And here are results, of course, I didn't really need to use a sub query for this, but it's just
an example to show you how to use it in the inclose.
OK, so that was a refresher on sub queries.