Accumulated sub query contains a reference to a table in the outer query.
As I mentioned in the previous lecture, in a normal sub query, the inner sub queries run first and
execute once they return values for the outer sub query.
But in a correlated some query, the sub query is executed for each of the outer query.
Correlated sub queries can be used when the sub query needs to return a different result for each row
in the out to query.
And I'll show you an example, surely.
Correlated sub queries can be used with logical operators and within any and all operators.
Let's query the eBay underscore countries table.
As you can see, a lot of countries do not have intermediate region IDs.
So let's do a correlated sub query where we only return those countries where there is an intermediate
region ID so I can type select a dot star from the Franchesco countries alias this as a.
We're into media region wide.
And I should type I should qualify this equals select p dot, Heidi from eBay, underscore country.
Underscore intermediate.
Be where?
A toe into media on the school region, on the school I.D..
Equals speed and terminate.
So what we're saying here is select countries from the Ebor countries table where the intermediate region,
it is equal to one of the ID fields in the EPA.
Underscore country.
Underscore intermediates table.
Now, if I query this in a sub query before the where clause.
What we're saying is here are a list of all of the intermediate region IDs.
And we're taking this from the EPA, this underscore country underscore intermediates table.
Now for the first record of the Ebor on this country's table.
Which is Afghanistan, and it doesn't have a region, it is it will execute this record first and it
will try to replace a door intermediate region here as no equals.
B, do it so this won't return any records.
But when we get to a country that does have an intermediate region like Angola.
This will take 80 for this record.
It will substitute it in this reference, which is referencing the outer table, and it will say select
ID from into Ebor Country Intermediate where 80 equals ID and therefore this workforce will select this
record.
So what we're essentially saying is select countries from the countries table where the region is in
the intermediate region ID field in the outer table is equal to the ID field in the inner subquery table.
So let's analyze the results.
So, as I said, what happens is that for every single room, one at a time in the undisclosed countries
table, the intermediate region ID value is passed onto the sub query.
Here, as you can see, the reference is for tabbouleh.
So for a first result here, the value A-T was posted.
And since we have 80 in this record here, we had a match.
As you can see, so in our sub query, only records where the I.T. field was 80.
Was returned.
And hence, the no returned was the scale value here, poverty, so let it run again.
And so this record was returned, so that's how the correlated subquery worked.
We can also use the where exists and where not exists clauses with correlated sub queries where exists
is used to test the existence of any record in a sub query and returns true if the record exists.
So in a correlated subquery wallaroos in the outer query that result in a true in the sub query are
returned.
Where not exists is used to test the nonexistence of any record in a sub query, it returns true if
the record doesn't exist.
These clauses are usually used with correlated sub queries.
OK, so let's do another example using the same.
EPA under four countries table and let's modify this existing example.
So let's replace this with where it exists and get rid of the equals operator.
So what we're doing here is we're still referencing a column from the out to query.
And we're saying basically, if the intermediate region ID field from the EPA countries table.
Equals the ID field from the FBI undiscovered country underscore intermediates table for the particular
record, then this will return true and that record will be displayed.
And it doesn't really matter what I select in the columns, because the sub crew is just testing for
existence, so I could just write one if I wanted to and if I hit run.
We return the same results.
And in this way, close, if I now type where one equals one, I will return every record.
Let me just close the parenthesis first.
I will now return every record because for each record in this top query, one will always equal one,
so every record will be displayed.
If I know right and one equals to two, I'll return no records because one never equals two.
So no records will.
This will be displayed.
Now, let me return only those countries with no intermediate region regionality so I can change this,
we're close to where not exists and I can right where a intermediate region I'd be to I'd.
Close parenthesis again.
And now we return only those results with no intermediate regionality.
OK, so that was a lecture on correlated sub queries.