A common table expression is a named ResultSet that exists temporarily as a table space and can be referred
to later in a select statement.
Because the city is stored as a table, space is retrieved from this table space rather than the base
tables used to create the CTY.
This can be beneficial when you have to reference the same table or query many times in a select statement.
The syntax for Qty is to type with, followed by the catchy name, you can then specify the column names
followed by the ASCII word.
You then open parentheses and type your select insert update or delete statement and then close the
parentheses.
You then finally select your columns by referencing the city itself.
I'm going to create a city which is just the empty table where the salaries are above two thousand.
So I'll type with followed by the city name and I'll just call it City Underscore School and I'll give
it four columns.
You name.
No.
Sal and Deb.
No, I'll type as followed by the subquery used to create the city, which will be Select Your Name
and Sal Adeptness from tempt fate Sal is created.
And two thousand.
And finally, I will select all columns referencing the city, notice that the select statement is referencing
the city and state run.
Here are all of our results where the salary is greater than two thousand.
We can also create multiple cities and separate them with commerce and perform selects on them.
Let's say I want to join all employees that have a salary of over 2000 to all departments that are either
in 10 or 20.
Well, I can create two cities and then perform a joint on both of these CTD.
So I can type a comma after my first S.T..
Type in the name of my new city, which, of course, city underscored that give a field of known as
Select Depner from Depth where depth and 10 and 20.
I will then finally perform and select on this, where I will select all records from the first city,
which of course Qty underscore EMP and Aliased as a.
And then I will then join in on the Second City Qty on this quartet, which are ASSP and I'll do the
join a quartet.
No, because they don't Depner.
And here.
And here are our results, all salaries greater than two thousand belonging to debt to know 10 or 20.
So that was just a short lecture on creating a common table expressions.