A recursive qty has one query that references itself.
They can enable you to process hierarchical data, in some cases, they can be used as alternatives
to higher hierarchical queries.
I mentioned in the Hierarchical Queries Lecture that my school does not permit hierarchical queries.
Well, in that instance, recursive keys can be used to query the AMP table in a hierarchical way as
an alternative.
The syntax for Recursive Qty is as follows, you start by typing with followed by the qty name as per
normal and specified the columns.
You then have two queries.
First, you have the anchor, the anchor clause sets the initial set of rules that are displayed at
the top of the hierarchy.
The anchor clause cannot reference the city itself, the anchor clause can be made up of said operators,
including union miners and et cetera.
You then must have a union all followed by the recursive clause of recursive clause, must reference
the CTY.
The recursive clause selects the next layer of the hierarchy based on the previous layer.
The anchor ResultSet is the first layer.
Aggregations, window functions, distinct clauses or devise limits are not allowed, you then apply
a select statement and reference the CTY to obtain the results at.
Now, I'll explain what happens in a recursive qty with some examples.
Recursive RCTs will definitely take some getting used to, and you'll probably have to do a few examples
before it becomes clear.
So I want you to take your time with this.
So in this query, the anchor query is to select empanel inane and manager from where the employee name
is either Blake or clonk.
So the table in the top right is the anchor table.
This is the first iteration of the city.
Now the recursive clause queries the AMP table, the same columns, employee name and manager.
But in the unclosed, the recursive clause queries the city and is performing a joint to our emptywheel
based on when that employee number of the anchor clause is equal to the manager or indeed of the employee
table.
So the anchor, which is the first iteration, is used to obtain the employee numbers from the CTY underscore,
and so after this iteration, we return the following table.
So this will be the result for all employees where their manager ID is that of Blake or clerk, the
second table is then used in the next iteration.
And now we're again looking for all employees where the manager it is either that of Alan's Ward's Martin's
attorneys, James or Millar's, but none of these guys are managers.
So that iteration stop and we've returned Oktay.
And finally, we query the results of our city, which will be the combination of the two tables on
the right.
So let me go through another scenario.
Let's say there's a table scale up on the school table, it holds one value, which is the number one
in a column called NP, which stands for number.
So the anchor query is going to return the following table, just a table with a column called N.
With a scalar value of one in it.
Now, the recursive clause will perform the iteration on the first anchor table, and it just adds one
to the value of an.
So then it will return to.
It then performs another iteration on the second table and returns three, which is two plus one, so
each iteration is performed on the latest return table.
They then combine together.
The iteration stops when NT becomes equal to four as per the where clause in the recursive clause.
In our final select statement, we return the CTY, which has entered as one, two and three.
As I mentioned in the previous example, if I didn't specify in as less than four as per the where clause
in the recursive sub query.
Then we would have an infinite loop.
Similarly.
If I had to join clause in the recursive query to be on onewhere was equal to and then we would always
return a match and the loop would just keep going.
Whereas when we match manager Editta to employee ID, we stop when there are no more managers left.
So you must be careful to avoid infinite loops.
So let's do some examples.
First, I'm going to create a scalar table with just the value of one.
In a column called End, so I'll type create table, scale the table and I'll give it one quarter of
an integer data type, then insert.
Into the table, the value of one.
So first, I'll execute this.
And then I'll execute the entire command.
So let's clear the table.
So now I want to create a recursive cty.
That references this scale table and contains the values from one three to five, to do that, I'll
type with Give my city a name of qty, underscore five, give it one column of N and type as followed
by the anchor query, which is select and from the scalar
table union or to my recursive clause which will be select and plus one from cty underscore five where
and is less than five.
So this is my Uncle Claus and this is my recursive clause, the recursive clause references the city,
the anchor clause creates the anchor table, which is used in the first iteration, and this query contains
just the value one.
So in the first iteration, one plus one will be two, and then in the second iteration, that value
of two will have one added to it and will keep going until the end is less than five.
We then select.
Records from.
Our recursive cty.
And as you can see, we return the records one three to five.
Now, let's see what happens if I remove the workload's.
So we're no longer limiting our results, so close parentheses and hit run.
We now get an infinite loop, which results in an error.
OK, so now let's do an example where I'm going to show you how to use recursive CTD instead of the
hierarchical sub queries in the previous section, if I want you to find all the direct and indirect
reports for Blak and clav using hierarchical queries, as you know, I would type select Mpondo name
manager from and start with Inamed in Blake and Clark and I would connect by Priya.
Employee equals manager.
Hey.
Are all of our reports for Blake?
And for Claire Miller reports to Clark and Allan Ward, Martin Turner and James reportedly now let's
get a similar result using recursive CTD.
So I would type with and I'll call it CTE underscore and and I'll give it three columns and put in your
name and manager and I'll define it as.
And in my anchor query, I will first select employees, you name and manager from Ms where Inamed in.
Blake.
And Clark, so this is my Uncle Claus, Isleton union, all I need, my recursive clause, I will select
AMPE.
AMP took in.
And DOT manager from Qty underscore AMP Buy will join it on the AMP table.
On Qty, underscore and.
To improve.
Beatles manager.
And I will then select staff from Qty on this call, and so let's analyze this.
The anchor query returns just like and clock.
As you can see.
So this is what the first iteration of the recursive clause will be done on, so we should get all of
Blake's direct reports and all of Clarke's direct reports.
This is because the recursive clause is looking at.
The CTM table and joining it on the table where the No.
Is equal to those employees where their manager is Blake clerk.
So now when I run this.
You can see this returns the same results as we got previously with a hierarchical sub query, although
it's in a slightly different order, you have Blakelock on the top and all of their direct reports in
the second iteration.
OK, now what if I wanted to find out all of the employees who report into King as well as the employees
who report into those reports until we have no more direct reports?
Well, I can type here where manager is now.
So this will return came as the inquiry because remember, King does not have a manager.
And what I'd also do is I'll add another column for and this will show us what the iteration will be
on for the anchor anchor clause, I'll give it one, because remember, that's the first iteration.
And then for the subsequent recursive clause, I will give it and plus one.
So Qty underscore m dot and.
Plus one.
So we now have four iterations, the first iteration will be fixing, and then we have the people who
report into King, which is Blakelock and Jones, then we have the people who report into Blakelock
and Jones.
And then for the fourth iteration, we have Adams and Smith who report into Scott and Ford, and after
that, Adams and Smith are not managers, so their manager right cannot be found and hence the iteration
stops.
So these examples were to show you how recursive keys can be useful.
Now, one final thing, if I change this join to be on an equal, Zampino will return an infinite loop.
As will always be able to match the employee with Yamoto.
So the way you structure your recursive key is crucial and it will take you some time to get your head
around this, but I suggest you keep practicing.