OK, so for this question, we need to use a recursive cty and have Klok as the anchor Resul.
We then need to join in the recursive search query and we join the AMP table to the city based on the
employee of the city to be the same as the manager right on the table.
So we type with S.T. on the score and give it three columns and know your name and manager as.
And so my anchor query, I'll type, select and pronounce your name manager from and where e name
equals clock union.
OK, and then select and don't no amp to rename AMP top manager.
From city to school and which is referencing the sub query.
Join and on Qty on this Klemp.
To employee equals camp dot manager and I then select staff from city school and.
And here, Ron.
So we now return clock along with his direct report, Milla.
And no, if you got the same result with a slightly different query, that's also fine.