OK, so for this question, we need to use a recursive cty and have Jones as the anchor result, we
then have to have a join in the recursive clause, part of the sub query, where we join the table to
the city based on the emperor of the city to be the manager ID in the table.
We then add another field, called it on the school.
No, so we can see which iteration number each result is from.
So we can type with and I'll call it qty underscore and and have employee in manager and later on the
school known as Select and no e name manager.
And I'll give the Italo a scalar value of one for the anchor result.
From.
And where e name equals Jones.
Within the union and then for the recursive clause we select and to enter and name and DOE manager and
then qty underscore ampe to end plus one from Qty, underscore and join in on qty underscore ampe.
And no equals and don't manager, we then select staff from our city.
And here on.
I'm sorry they should be on this call.
No.
And here on.
And now here are results we can see Jones as part of the anchor query, is in the first iteration and
then Scott and forward report into Jones.
As part of the second iteration.
And then the third iteration, we have Adams and Smith, who report to Scott and Ford as part of the
final iteration and after Adams and Smith do not have manager, it's because Adams and Smith are not
managers to any other employees.
So what iteration and.