I recall Escudo has hierarchical queries that are used specifically for data that is hierarchical,
these queries allow you to arrange the rows of these tables in hierarchical order.
Hierarchical data is data that contains a parent child relationship.
For example, organizational data such as the empty pool that we query, there are two fields the employee
and the manager field.
The manager field is the parent column and the employee field is the child column.
Other examples of hierarchical data include general ledger data, for example, you have costs that
belong to specific subaccount codes and these subaccount codes roll up into account codes.
You also have product hierarchies where you have some products and product categories.
There are many other hierarchical data set examples, too, but for this section will specifically be
working on our table.
This slide shows our table data arranged in its tree structure so you can see the hierarchy.
Right at the top is King, who is the president.
He does not have a manager and below King we have Jones Lake and Clark.
This is the next level down and is referred to as level two in the hierarchy.
Jones has two reports, Scott and Forward Blake has five reports, Alan Ward, Martin Turner and James
and Clark has one report.
Miller, this is referred to as level three.
Then in the next level, we have Adams, who reports to Scott and Smith, who reports to Ford, this
is referred to as level four.
All of the so-called employees can be referred to as parents or roots as they have employees who reporting
into them.
So this is our hierarchy now when we look at the table in Oracle, it's not so clear compared to this
diagram.
This is because the data is not arranged in hierarchical order, and that's why we use hierarchical
queries, as you will see in the coming lectures.
The syntax for hierarchical queries is shown on the screen, and the bits highlighted in orange are
y will go through in turn in the coming lectures.
So for now, just keep this as a reference and I will explain all of the pseudo columns, functions
and clauses.