The connect by prior clause defines the parent and child columns in your table, the column immediately
following the prior keyword is the child column.
OK, so let's see some examples of this.
I'm going to select all columns from the table.
Now, I want to use the Kinect because.
And have no problem as the child him and the manager column has the parent column to do that.
I totally connect by prior and immediately following the prior Keywood I typed in because that's the
child column equals manager.
So here is where we are defining our parent child relationship with the child and manager as the parent.
And yet.
Before I do, I'm going to increase the limit.
OK, so from our results.
We could see that we've returned thirty nine rows, our dataset only has 14.
So the reason for this is because if we do not specify the start with close and I will explain the start
with close, surely then we return the result for each route slash parent.
So let me show you, you recall that the first result in our record is Scott empaneling seven, seven,
eight, eight, and he has one report, Adams.
Both of them report into joint.
Ford, which is the third row, also has one report, Smith and both of them also report into Jones.
So this the first four rows.
Actually use Jones as the root.
And then from the fifth through, we have Alan, James, Turner, Martin and Ward.
They will report into Blake.
This continues until every parent has been evaluated.
So essentially, this is iterating with each parent as the root.
So let's say I want to see the results only with Jones as the root.
Well, I can type start with before the connect by clause to start with clause specifies which routes
to include.
So if I want to include Jones, I can type.
Before the connect by clothes start with empire equals seven, five, six, six.
And now here we have Jones with all of his direct and indirect reports.
Now, what if we wanted to see King, who's the president, as the root?
Well, we can change the empire to be King's empire, which is seven, eight, three nine.
And now we have all 14 crews, because everyone reports indicate you'll note that Kim does not have
a manager, right.
So we could also specify talk with manager is No.
And we would get the same results.
And note that whatever column immediately follows the prior Keywood is referred to as the child column.
So if I swapped the prior to be on the other side.
Then the manager field is deemed to be the child column and the field is the parent, so we're now actually
changing the direction of the tree.
So let's check the result.
As you can see, we only return one result this time, and that is because if we change the direction
of the tree, there is nobody above.
So let's test this for James.
So Jones has an inferno of seven, five, six, six.
Now we can see everybody above Jones, which is just king.
And now if I swapped the premier over again.
We can see everyone below Jones and I can also swap around manager, and I'm not here to reverse the
direction as well.
So remember to type prior before you input your child in the equation.