Level is a pseudo problem that can be used in the select statement only when iConnect connect by clause
is used and shows the level in the hierarchy for each record.
Previously in the tree structure, I showed you the four levels of the hierarchy.
So if I query the map table with King as the route and using the connect by clause as follows.
It's not so clear to see the level for each record belongs to in the hierarchy.
So if you want the level, you can just type.
After qualifying this asterisk.
Level.
And now we can see the full.
Levels one, two, three, four, four, the hierarchy, so it's clear to see.
That he is Blake.
And here are all of his reports as the one level below.
So level one.
Has leveled to reporting into it.
Jones.
Clark.
And I missed Flakier.
And then level two has level three reporting it into it, and then level three has level for reporting
into it.
So let's do this again now, this time with Blakers, the route with no equals.
Seven, six, nine, eight.
So whoever the root is will be level one.
And as we can see, Blake is level one and he has five reports, high level to.
So let's do it now for Jones, and you'll recall that he has two reports and his reports have reports,
so we expect three levels.
Jones has an emperor of seven, five, six, six.
And as you can see, we get three levels, so level is a really useful pseudo problem to show you the
level that each record belongs to.
And note once again that it can only be used when the connect by clause has been used.