Connect Beirut can be used in the select statement to return the root value in each word, you just
specify the column of the record to return.
Connect Beirut is used in the select statement.
The syntax is to type connect Beirut and then the name of the column to return from the root record.
So if I query the table with King as the root and using the connect by clause as follows.
You can see that King is the route and he's on the top.
So if I then type followed by Connect by route and the name calling.
We now have King repeated in each row, and we can also alias this caller.
As you can see.
Now, let's do the same, but this time with Jones as the root, so where employee start with employees
equals seven, five, six, six.
Now we have Jones.
And if I don't want to return the name, I can just type another column.
So let's say emperor.
And instead of the name, we return the employee ID now let's see what happens when we don't have to
start with field.
So we're using multiple routes.
So if I delete this Antikythera.
So now we can see.
The employee number that each role belongs to.
And that makes it much clearer to understand who the root is, and it will become even clearer if I
change this to you name again.
So now we can see all the records where Scott is, the route forward, Allen James and so on.
This connect bypass function shows you the path up to the route for each node, you just define a separator
and just like the connect by path and level, it's used in the select statement.
And the function takes two parameters, the column name and the separator, which is a character.
So let's use this connect bypass in our previous query with Jones as the root, so I will type, select
and dot star system to connect dots, um, underscore sorry I on this call path and I will type e name
and specify the dash as the separator.
From.
And I would like it to start with no equals seven, five, six, six.
Connect high pressure, temperature equals manager and hit run.
So now in our results, we can see the path, we can make this clearer by also showing level.
We can see that level one just has one employee and level two has two employees.
Let's go to Jones now.
Let's do this by commenting out.
Start with.
And we can see that level one just has one again, level two as two and so on, and we can also change
this instead of each name to the emperor and change the dash.
To be a forward slash.
As you can see, OK, great, so that was showing you how to use, connect, bypass and connect by.