If we use the order by close, then we break the hierarchical ordering of the data using order by siblings
preserves the hierarchy primarily and then orders the results by the specified columns.
The order by siblings clause can only be used in hierarchical queries, so if I query the table with
Blake as the root and using the connect by clause as follows.
Start with M equals seven.
Six, nine, eight, four black connect by prior and equals manager and her.
So here we have Blakers, our route.
And all of his reports.
So now let's use the order by close.
An order based on your name ascending and its default by ascending to I don't need to write it.
Now, as you can see, we've actually broken the hierarchy, Blake is no longer at the top.
So let's use order siblings by instead.
Now, as you can see, we retain the hierarchy, but now the siblings.
In level two are arranged in alphabetical order, AJ MTW.
So that's just a short lecture showing you how to order your results, but retain the hierarchy primarily.