You can format your results so that they're more readable using the L pad function, the Árpád function
pad the string with another string up to a certain length.
It takes three parameters, the so string, which should be a column.
The total length of the string should be and the padding character.
So if your string has a length of five but only four characters, then the remaining character will
be padded by one additional part character on the left side.
So let's first query your results with King as the root, so I'll select NPR top staff level from AMP.
Start with AMP no equals.
Seven, eight, three, nine.
Connected by prior employer, he was manager and run.
OK, so it's hard to tell here where each parent is looking.
Now, if I use L pad, L pad and I will specified in.
Has the string.
Followed by the length, which will be the length function to the evening, plus the additional padding
character, which I'll just have as level, so it will be padded by one additional character if the
level is one two, if the level is two and so on, and the padding character will be the greatest and
simple.
And I'll use this as your name again, your name on the school had.
And hit, run.
Now we can see.
King is the top, and he has one character below him, we have Jones and then Jones, whose quotes got
reporting into him, and then Scott has Adams reporting into him.
So it's clear to see now the structure.
So that's just a quick tip on formatting your results to make your hierarchy a little bit more readable.