You can filter your records using the workload's, so let us query the table with King as the root
and I'll actually address this at that level.
And that is King's employee ID.
OK, so let's say I do not want to return Blake.
I can just use a workload's before they start with claws and type with Infinera does not equal.
Seven, six, nine, eight, which is Blake's employee number.
And as you can see, Blake is no longer returned, but we do have Blake's direct reports.
If we want to exclude Blake's direct and indirect reports to, then instead of using the word close,
we can just add the clause to the connect by clause and type where and no does not equal.
Seven, six, nine, eight.
And now when I hit run.
Not only do we not return blank, but we also do not return his direct or indirect reports.
So that would also be the people who report into the people that report into black.
So, as you can see, specifying your condition in the connect by clause will mean that the exclusion
or the condition applies to the children to.