OK, so for this question, we actually need to reverse the direction and go up from Smith all the way
to King so we can do that by swapping the employee and manager in the connect by close.
And we need the manager to be the child and the employee to be the parent column.
So that's type select start from and start with.
Employer equals seven three six nine.
Which is Smith's employee number, and then we connect by prior to this time specified manager equals
employee.
So now we actually go from Smith has the root to food, Jones and King.
And he is treated as the parent node.
As a result, we can see all the people that he reports in to and who they in turn report into uptaking.
Who is the president?