So this question is a bit trickier and actually involves using some queries.
So let's do this in part first, let's use the hierarchical query to have Jones as the root, so I'll
select all films from the MPT.
Start with Jones Employee ID.
And then connect by Priya and his manager.
OK, so now we have all employees who directly report to Jones or indirectly report into Jones.
So and Ford directly reporting to Jones.
Adams reports to Scott and Smith reports to Ford, so they both indirectly report to Jones.
So now we just need to sum all of these salaries, excluding Jones, so let's use a workload's where
Mpondo.
Does not equal seven, five, six, six.
And now we just need to sign this so we can actually use this as a subquery sign close in parenthesis,
open, close and then just hide.
Select some sound from.
And are.
And the answer is seven thousand nine hundred.
You know, if you found another way to get to the same answer using hierarchical queries, then that's
also fine.