Analytical functions are quite different to standard esquibel functions in terms of syntax, mainly
because they use the Overkill's, which we will discuss in the coming lectures, but because the syntax
is so different, it can be difficult to understand analytical functions and so they are often avoided.
However, analytical functions are extremely powerful and very useful.
And I'll show you an example of this now.
So we're in Oracle APACS and I want to look at the countries table.
So let's select staff from undisclosed countries.
So increase the limit to 500.
Now, let's say I want to find the percentage of total region population.
For each country, so, for example, Ireland belongs to Region 20.
Its population is approximately four point nine million.
I want another row in this table to have this as a percentage of the total population for region wide
20.
So without using window functions, this can be done by joining an aggregated countries table grouped
by region ID and some population, that table can then be joined back to this table to give the total
population for Region 20.
We would then apply a mathematical operator.
To divide the population by country to the population, by region wide and multiply that by one hundred
to get the percentage.
So let me show you, in order to get the aggregated table, I would select some population.
And I also selected region and it because that's what we're grouping by from Libya and so countries
grouped by region to underscore it.
So now we have the total population for each region in the.
So what I want to do is join this back to the industrial countries table.
So this will be a sub query.
So first, let me select and then leave this blank as I'll populate the columns shortly from eBay and
ask all countries and I'll abbreviate as a an abbreviated, says B..
I didn't specify left join.
And then this is the table I would like to let you use the key word, A, to reach and underscore it,
it would be region under security.
Now, let's select the columns I would like to populate.
So from tabouli, which is the Ebor and School Countries table, I would like the name of the country,
I would like the region, I'd I would like the population.
And from Table B, I would like to the sum of population, which will be the region population, and
I'll just aliased that here as region underscore pop, so be your region.
Pundits call pop.
And now I would like a calculated formula which takes the population of the country divided by the region,
population multiplies it by 100 to get the percentage.
So that would be.
A population divided by bitter region and the scope multiplied by one hundred and I can use the round
function to round that to decimal places, and I'll call that as a percent of region total.
And hit, run.
So now, as you can see, the population of Ireland.
Is zero point six five percent of the total region population for region wide 20, the total of Israel
is zero point one nine percent of the total region population of region wide, 30 and so on.
As you can see, this works, but this isn't exactly a straightforward query for what is a relatively
straightforward task.
So let's have a quick look at the explainer plan, as you can see, the cost for this query is seven.
So we'll just keep that in mind for now.
Now, let me use analytical functions to answer the same question.
Don't worry about the syntax I'm about to use, a lot of it will seem unfamiliar to you if you're not
if you've not used analytical functions before.
But I will cover this in the coming lectures.
So let's get rid of this query.
And I type select name population
regionality.
And now for my analytical functions, so first I do some population use the over clause partitioned
by region on the right, this will give me the total population for the region.
It.
So I can actually just divide the population by this analytical function.
And then multiply it by one hundred to get the percentage and I can use the round function again, the
second place I can use the round function again to two decimal places as a percent of region topped.
What you say about.
From EPA and school countries.
So as you can see.
If I.
Try to find Ireland, so as you can see, if I find Ireland, we get the same answer of zero point six
five and we've been able to perform the same query.
Much more efficiently in terms of syntax, and if I look at the explain turn to this.
You can see.
That this time the cost is four compared to seven and there are much fewer operations being performed.
So as I was saying, analytical functions can be very powerful.
So actually, Slide's analytical functions are also referred to as window functions.
This is because they compute their results based on a window of one or more rows.
So in the example, we just covered the window with region on this call, Heidi.
Also, as you've seen, unlike aggregation functions, analytical functions do not collapse rows, but
they are still able to compute aggregated values.
The syntax for analytical functions is as follows first, you specify the analytical function.
This can be an aggregation function like some or count.
For example, I will cover these analytical functions in more detail in this section.
But for the following examples, in the next few lectures, we will be using some.
The over clause is what designates the function as an analytical function inside the over clause, we
have the partition by this is the grouping we would like.
So in our previous example, we had partition by region on the school ID.
We can also partition by more than one column.
You can also order your results by using the order by clause.
But note that this will order the results based on the results of the partition by clause.
So, for example, if we partition by region on the school I.D. and order by country name, then the
country names will be ordered for the region ID partition.
I'll elaborate on this in the coming lectures.
The window frame defines the window itself in our earlier example.
We did not define a window frame, so by default it was rose unbounded proceeding and unbounded following,
meaning to use all the rows in the partition.
One thing to note about the syntax is that although the partition by the order by and the window frame
clauses are not mandatory, they must follow the same order.
So if you are using a partition by an order by you must specify the partition by before the order.
And if you're using a window frame, in addition to a partition by an order by the window frame must
be specified at the end.
Don't worry if this is confusing for you right now, I'll dive into all aspects of the syntax and covid
different scenarios with examples.
By the end of this section, you should be confident with analytical functions.
But please do ensure you follow all the lectures and try to code along with me if you can.