The Overlords is what determines the partitioning and ordering of the Rousset before the window function
itself is a polite.
As you've seen in this context, within the over clause, you can specify the partition, the ordering
and the window frame itself.
If you do not specify any partition, then the over clause applies to the entire table.
Let me show you.
Let's use the over clause with some aggregation on populations in the countries table so we can type
select name, comma, some population and then just specify over with no partitioning, ordering or
window frames in parentheses and then from every underscore countries.
So as you can see, we return seven point seven billion, this is the sum of the population for the
entire table.
Because we haven't specified any partition or window frame, the function has summed all rose in the
table if I just select some population to confirm this.
You can see that the some of the population is the same.
I will cover the partition by close order, by close and window frames in the next lecture's.
But as you've seen, if you just use the overgrowth on its own, it applies the window function to every
row in the query table.
This is also an alternative to applying an aggregation without using the group because.