So we've seen that if we apply the over clause with no partition, then there's some aggregation function
applies to all those in the entire table.
We can specify partitions for our window functions, for example, if we want the sum returned for the
total region, for that specific role, we can state partition by region it.
So if the road has a region idea of 10, then we will return the total population for region wide 10.
So to apply an analytical function which is partitioned by region wide, I can type select name, which
is the country name population, just so I can compare the population for the country to the population,
for the total region wide region on underscore ID and then the actual analytical function, which is
some population, and then within the overlord's type partition by region.
Underscore right from Epper underscore countries.
So this returns.
The total population for region is 10.
And then if I scroll down, you can see the total population.
For regionality 20.
And so on with region 30.
So there's some aggregation function is partitioned by region, and it will calculate at a low level
the total population.
For the region, I'd of that road.
So in the first row, it will calculate the total population for region wide 10.
We can also partition by multiple columns.
Let me now partition by region and subregion.
And now the population is calculated for both the region and the subregion.
Let me make this clear by actually including the sub region, it is in the results.
So now the population four region is 10 and subregion 10 is six hundred and forty eight million.
And as I scroll down.
As soon as the subregion, it changes to 80, we've calculated the total population for region wide
10 and subregion ID 80, whereas in the previous example we calculated the entire population for region
10.
OK, so that was a lecture on how to include politicians in your analytical functions, give it some
practice in your own time, and move on to the next lecture once you're comfortable with this.