The order by crews is used to order the rows and each partition.
You can order by more than one column.
So let's use an analytical function to some the population and order it by region into ascending.
So let's select a name which is a country name population.
Regionality.
And then the analytical function.
So while some population just correct that over and I'll specify order by region is ascending and ascending
is the default.
So even if I wasn't to specify anything, it would be ordered in ascending order from evah underscore
countries.
Right.
So as you can see, the results are ordered by region wide and here, as you can see, the total population
is still the same.
And since we haven't applied a partition, the order by clause in the over clause applies to the entire
table and it's ordered by region from low.
Ty.
OK, so now let's order by region and subregion ID
and Allied Subregion ID as a column.
And I'll execute.
So now we have the table.
Ordered by region and subregion, it from Lord.
Ty.
If I was to now specify a politician.
By region, underscore I.D. and order by sub region ID and I'll specify descending for this time from
high to low.
You can see now each individual partition, which is region 10.
So the population has now been calculated for region wide 10, but it's also ordered by subregion ID
descending.
So it goes from eight to 10 and then we'll move on to the next partition of twenty.
And then we have a new value in the road for 20 and they were range from high.
Tylo.