This lecture is critical to mastering analytical functions.
So please make sure you follow along after you apply your partitions and order by Krause's, you have
to define a window frame.
The window frame defines the rows that are used in the analytical function.
So if we use to some aggregation, then for each partition of the table, the window frame defines which
rose to some, hence the term window frame in a partition as you move down each room.
You have the current rows and you have the rows which are preceding the current row, and you also have
the rows which are following the current row.
Of course, if your current role is at the top or bottom of the partition, then there are no preceding
or following roles.
So in the illustration, we have a partition from a table.
In that partition, we have the current.
And then you have another group that is in rose above it in the partition.
We turn that as in proceeding.
So if it was two rows proceeding, we would say two proceeding.
You have another group that comes and goes after and we say and following, if it came three weeks after,
we would take three following.
The same applies for every single politician.
This slide shows the definitions of the different bounds, all definitions include the current.
I've attached this slide as a resource to this lecture.
So you already know what roads are in a table, a range is a value, and in your window frame you include
all roads where the value is within that defined range.
I will elaborate on this shortly.
When defining just one bound you type rows or range, followed by the bound.
For example, Rose, one proceeding or range, one proceeding.
When defining lower and upper bounds, you type the rows or range followed by the between Keywood.
The lower bound and the upper bound.
The lower bound must come before the upper bound.
So in the left side, we have an extract of a table partition, this is fake data and has not been extracted
from the country's table.
It's just, for example, purposes.
We've tried to get the some of the population partitioned by region and ordered by subregion ID and
defined the window frame as rose unbounded preceding.
The table is the partition four way region, it equals 20, so it's looking at the partition where region
it is 20.
This means that for the some of the population, the window frame is all the rows before the current
row and the current row itself.
Which you can see highlighted in the green box.
And if you take the total.
The sum would be fifty eight million, five hundred thousand.
On the right table, we have the same formula, except the window frame is now defined between unbounded
proceeding and one following.
So now we take all those preceding the current row and one row after the current row, which you can
see highlighted in green.
So the sum of the population is now fifty eight million, five hundred and ten thousand.
And remember, both of the tables on the slide are partitions, and for each partition in the context
of each row, we are defining a window frame.
So as you go down through the window, frame will also move down with that row.
Now, instead of roads, we're using range in the window frame, the difference with using range is
that it considers a range of numerical values and compares them to the common value for the column that
has been used in the order.
Because if you do not have anything in your order, because you cannot use range, you must also only
have one expression in your order, because when using wrench.
So when we're using rows rather than range and we see one proceeding, for example, that means one
road.
But when we say one preceding Farangis, it means one unit of the value that's being evaluated.
So if we have subregions I.D. that is being used in our order because the current row has a subregion
idea of 20, then one proceeding would mean subregion idea of 19 as 20, minus one is 19.
And that doesn't exist in our table.
So in the example on the left, we have our politician the same as before, and our query is ordered
by subregion ID.
But in the window frame, we say range 10 proceeding because remember, the preceding subregion ID value
from our current view is 20, which is 10 lower since we have subregion in the order, because this
is what the range considers.
So the current route has a subregion of 30.
And this is ordered so we can see that 10 proceeding, which is 30, minus 10 equals 20.
So that is the range that is used in our window frame for the current row, which is all subregion yds
between the range 20 and 30.
And that is highlighted in green.
So for the current row, the sum of the population would be fifty five million, five hundred thousand.
For the right side partition, we use a range between unbounded proceeding and 10 following.
So we start right at the top and go ten following the value of the subregion ID in the current row,
since the subregion ID in the current row is 30.
We do 30 plus 10 equals 40, but as you can see, there are two roles which belong to Country EAF.
That are part of subregion 40, so they are both included.
It looks for the range of values for subregion ID to select all the rows preceding the current row.
Up to subregion 40.
And some of the population for the current road would be 78 million, five hundred and ten thousand.
If you have nothing specified for the window frame and if the order is specified, then the default
window frame is range between inbounded proceeding and current row.
The highlighted green shading shows you the window frame for the current road.
If you have not specified an order by and have not included a window frame in your overflows, then
the default specification is rows between unbounded proceeding and unbounded following.
The highlighted green shading is the default window frame for the current work, and that just takes
all values in that politician.