Now, let's start with some examples by defining which rose to use in window frame.
I'm using the country's tables, too, and I want to partition by regionality and subregion it and also
order it by subregions it.
So let's start by using Rose unbounded proceeding and unbounded following.
So I'll select a name which is a country name, regionality sub region IT population.
And now I would define my analytical function, which I will be the sum of the population over partition
by region and the security and sub region and the security, I also order the partition by sub region
it.
And now to define my window frame, I'll type Rose Inbounded.
Proceeding and inbounded following, and I'll name that as a from EPA undisclosed countries.
Now let's hear from.
Got the between keyword.
So if we look at problem A, we can see that we've defined each partition as a combination of the region
and the sub region, it.
So for some reason, it 10 and regionality 10.
We have the total population, which I think is six hundred and forty eight million.
When we scroll down.
And we get to subregion it.
Of 80.
We recalculate the total population for region wide 10 and sub region 80, which is three hundred and
sixty seven million approximately.
And this is because we've defined unbounded proceeding and unbounded following as the window frame.
So for each row.
For that specific politician, which in our case, the politician is defined by each distinct regional
and subregional combination, the some formula will take all roles for each politician.
Now, let's do another analytical function.
Using the same.
Partitioned by an order by criteria.
So I'll just copy and paste it, and this time I'll define the partition as one proceeding and one follow
me, so I'll type rose, one rose between the other, between Keywood, one proceeding and one following,
and I'll call that as B I let it run.
Now, let's see what's happening here.
So for Colombe, each window frame again.
Is defined within the partition of region wide and subregion.
I did so for column B again, we're using the partition of regionality and subregion.
But for the window frame, we're defining one proceeding and one following in the context of the current
row.
So for Jamaica.
Nothing is proceeding in.
But we have the population of Honduras following it.
So we take.
Two million, nine hundred and forty thousand and add that to the population of Honduras, which is
approximately nine point seven million, and we get our result here, which is the sum of these two
populations.
And then when we get to our next route, which is Honduras, this time for the window frame, we have
one proceeding, we have the current route and we have one following.
So this value.
Of one hundred and forty million is the sum of the population of Mexico, Honduras and Jamaica, and
we continue doing that until we get to the end of the partition.
Which is Grenada.
And this value of four hundred and two thousand eight hundred and thirty five would be the sum of French
Guiana plus Granada, because remember we're at the end of the partition.
So the following value of Canada is actually part of a different partition because the subregion, it
is 80.
So we just take the sum of this valley and this value.
And again, when we start with Canada, which is at the new partition, this valley would be the sum
of the current group and one following because remember, there is nothing preceding this partition.
So let's do one more example just to cement our understanding and this time all the current road and
to follow.
So I'll just.
Copy this and modify it, palitha ac.
Rows between current row and two following.
And here, Ron.
So now for each politician, we take the value of the current population, which will be Tumaco in this
current group, which would be the top rate, and then at the population of Honduras and Mexico to get
the value of one hundred and forty million.
So it's essentially just an offset of B by one word, and remember, just as with Colombe, each politician
changes.
With the next subregion, it.