Let's now move on to using range to define our window frame.
I want to partition by regionality and order by subregions, it but first let's select all the columns
from our countries table.
And now for the analytical function of some population, again, over partition by region wide order
by sub region it.
And define the range between one proceeding and one following.
As a.
From EPA, undisclosed countries and here.
So now we're using values from the subregion, it in our range as that is in the autobio clause.
So by saying one proceeding and one following, it means that when we are looking at subregion it of
ten, we're looking for the range in each individual partition.
With the subregion, it is nine and 11.
So when we were in and it when we were in the region, 90, 10 partition.
We can see subregion ID 10 and the next subregion, it is 80.
So we don't have one proceeding and one following in this context, because 80 is actually 70 following
10.
So this valley, which is six hundred and forty eight million.
Just takes the value from the current range, which will be the regionality 10 and the subregion region
10.
So let's try Zevo proceeding.
And 74 following, because we know in our petition for Region 10, we have subregion eight, 10 and
subregion ID 80.
So if I do zero proceeding and 70 following, I expect this value for the partition region at 10 and
subregion 80 10 to increase to be the total for region and 10 because 70 following, which is 10 plus
70 is 80.
So let's test that theory.
I'll just copy this, Al.
We need to be 10 years zero preceding and 70 following.
Get rid of that comma and run.
And now, as you can see.
You'll recognize that just over one billion is actually the total for each night 10.
And if I scroll down.
Six for eight million plus three six, seven million.
Is this value over here?
And when we are in the context of Canada, which is.
So which is region wide 10 and subregion 80.
We get the same value, and this is because zero preceding 80 is 80 and 70, following would be one
hundred and fifty.
But we don't have subregion ID in the range of 80 to 150 as we go to the next partition.
So we know the value here, we just take the value for Regenhard 10 and subregion 80.