So I appreciate that might be a lot to take in, but let's run through some examples using our country's
table.
Let's first look at how the default window frame works when we don't specify anything for the window
frame.
So let's type select name, which is the country name region.
Underscore it because that's what we're going to partition by subregion underscore.
Right.
Because that's what we can order by the population, because that's what we're going to do our analytical
function on.
And then the first analytical function, which will be some of population
over.
Partition by region underscore it, and I'll include an order by clause, sub, underscore region,
underscore it, but I won't specify a window frame.
All alias.
This is a.
I'll do another analytical function where I'll do some of population over partition by region, underscore
it, and this time I won't specify an order by or the window frame and I'll add that as be and will
type from every underscore countries.
And let me just select 500000.
And here right now, let's evaluate our results.
So I want you to understand the difference between the columns A and B.
For both, we have not specified the actual window frame for column A. We have partition by region and
order by subregion subregions.
Since we've specified the order by.
But not defying the window frame, the range is between unbounded preceding and current.
Whereas for Colombe, we specified the partition by, but we've not specified the order by or the window
frame.
So the default for that would be rose, unbounded proceeding and inbounded following, so Colombe continues
the summation for the entire partition.
So this value, which is just over one billion, is the sum of the population for region ICD 10.
And as we get to a new region, it it then takes the sum of region into 20, whereas for column A,
we continue the partition.
Until we get to a new subregion, I'd say this some.
Would be for regionality 10 and subregion ID 10.
So then it's currently six hundred and forty million.
And as we get to subregion, I'd 80, the value goes up.
To one million, to over one billion, so it takes the value for subregion ID 10.
And it adds it to the value for some reason.
So it continues something on because remember, it's doing range inbounded proceeding and current road.
So when you're at Canada, which is regionality 10 and subregion 80, inbounded proceeding would also
include subregion 10.
And as we get to a new partition, we start again.
So this Time column, again, is lower than Colombia because Colombia has calculated the population
for the entire partition of Region 20, whereas so far Column A. has only calculated the sum of population
for region in the 20 and subregion 70.
So as we go down to the next subregion and we're still in partition for region 80-20, we continue to
add on and it slowly will accumulate.
Until we get the same value in both columns.
So I hope you understand what's going on with Columns A and B.