I wanted to show a quick one analytical functions when using single bounce, specifically the following
single bound in your window frame.
As you know, Rose, and proceeding is the same as saying rose between and proceeding and current work.
Let me show you some iSelect name.
Population.
For that region Heidi and sub region, Heidi.
And now that an analytical function where I am partitioning by region wide and subregional
ordering by sub region it.
And for the window frame, I'll specify rose to preceding.
And now occupy this.
And I will change the window frame to rose between two proceeding and current row from undisclosed countries.
So these two should be exactly the same because those two proceeding should be the same, the same rows
between two proceeding and current.
And as you can see.
If you compare the two numbers.
There will be exactly the same.
Even as we get to the next partition, surely.
And here we go.
So, as I said, Rose to proceeding is the same as rose between two proceeding and current road rules
and following means the same thing as rose between current rule and following.
But when we use the following as a single bound, for some reason the query fails.
Let me show you.
So I will comment this out.
And I will change proceeding to following.
Were.
Missing keyword now if I change this to preceding.
The query works, so if you need an following, then a workaround would be to take.
Between.
Current road and to following, and if I come to south.
You can see that works and we already know.
That between current and following should be the same as to follow me, so I just wanted to flag that
as a bit of a quirk to look out for.