So, as you know, in all of our previous examples, we've used the some aggregation function, but
now let's go over the other aggregation functions as well.
In some examples, we'll use the country's table and will apply the aggregation functions on the population
field.
So let's try to select a name which is the country name.
I also had regionality.
And now I'll apply the same aggregation which we've already been using, and to make this an analytical
function, I'll use the clues, but I won't specify anything inside the over clause.
So this analytical function will be applied across the entire table, and I'll do that for the rest
of the aggregations as well.
From eBay, undisclosed countries, let's hit, run.
Hyperbola.
I mean.
Greg.
OK, so as I said, because we've applied the over clause.
And no parameters within the over clause.
These aggregation functions are applied to the entire table, so the sum of the population for all countries
is seven point seven billion.
The minimum population is zero, the maximum population is one point four billion.
There are two hundred and forty nine votes and the average population is approximately thirty one million.
OK, so now let's apply a partition in our over clause, we will partition by region it and I will copy
that
into all of the analytical functions.
And here are.
So now this time we are partitioning by region, and so the sum of the population for region wide 10
is one billion.
The minimum population is zero.
The maximum population is three hundred and twenty nine million.
There are fifty seven countries in Region 10 and the average average population is approximately 17
million.
If I now go down to the next region.
The values change.
So the population is now what looks to be seven hundred and forty seven million, the minimum population
is a seven hundred and ninety nine.
The maximum population is one hundred and forty five million.
Two hundred forty six million approximately.
There are fifty one countries and the average population is lower than region ten at approximately fourteen
point seven million.