Let's go over the analytical window functions.
Let's start with the lack function, the lack function returns a value from a previous role off the
table.
It takes in three parameters.
The first parameter is the expression.
This can be a field like population or name, and it can also include a field that has an inbuilt function
applied to it.
Second parameter is the offset by default.
This is one meaning that it takes the value from the previous row.
If you typed two, it would take the value from two rows above the current.
The third parameter is the value to display if there are no previous values by default.
This is No.
The lack analytic function should also have an order by inside the overlords, if you're using Oracle
for other database management systems such as MySQL, you may not need to specify an order by clause.
It just depends based on what database management system you're using.
Different ones will have different requirements.
OK, so let's revisit the country's table, let's select the field, name and population and apply the
like function on the name field.
So I'll select a name which is a country name population, and I apply like to the name field and the
overlord's.
And remember, we need to specify an order by when using the over clause, so I'll order by name.
Now I'm just using one parameter in my like function.
From EPA and school countries.
And here on.
OK, so you can see from my results.
In to.
We have Afghanistan in our light column and we can see the previous role for the name column is Afghanistan.
In the first row, we have a null value.
This is because when you're on the first row, there are no values above it.
OK, so let's do another example.
Now.
And in the second parameter of the leg function, which is its offset, let's talk to so note that we
did not specify a second parameter in the leg function in this analytical function and therefore the
default value was one.
So I'll type like name to over order by name.
And here.
From our results, we can now see that in our second like call we have to Noles as the offset is to
and Afghanistan is now in the third row.
So if we're in the third row and we go to above, we have Afghanistan and then again, everything is
offset.
So let's do one more example.
And this time in the third parameter of the leg function, we will change the default value to blank.
So we just copy this and now in the third parameter, I will type blank.
And so now, instead of the nulls, the default value that's populated is blank.
The lead function is just the opposite of the leg function, the syntax is the same apart from typing
like you type lead.
And instead of returning the previous rose value, it returns the following news value.
OK.
So let's change our flag queries to lead
a..
And as I said, instead of the previous values, it takes the next values, so the first rule in our
first live column, we have Albania.
Which is the next problem down.
And here we have Algeria, which is the second column down, and remember in our second query we specified
the default is two.
If we scroll all the way down the table, we can see that the nulls and the blanks are populated at
the end.
And that is because after Åland Islands, there are no values.
The entire function divides the rows as equally as possible within each partition.
It takes one parameter, which is for the number of groups.
It must also be used with the order by clause because it is the values in the columns or expression
used in the order by clause that will determine the groupings.
So let's use the entire function to divide the field into three groups.
So let me delete this and we'll type.
Name population and then entitled and I'll specify three groups over older by population and here.
Now our data is altered by population and we have one.
Group to.
And then finally, Group three, so the three groups have been as evenly distributed as possible based
on the ordering of population that we've specified, if we were to partition by region, I'd.
And if I was tied for each night as a field.
We would have three groups specified for each partition.
And then once we get to the next partition, we start again.
If I change this to untill five.
We now have.
Five groups partitioned as evenly as possible based on the population order.
The end value function brings the value within an analytic window.
It takes two parameters.
The column or the expression you wish to return and the end value unlikely like lead or entail functions,
you don't need to use the order by clause.
So let's return the value from the name column.
So I'll select name, population and value and I'll specify the name field.
And the second value is what I wish to return and apply the over clause.
So we're using the entire table as our window frame.
He just thinks that.
Now, as you can see, the second venue is Isle of Man, and that is what we return in our value column.
Now, let's use a partition and partition this by region and
let me add region here and here.
So now the second value in the partition for region and 10 is Martinek.
The second value for the partition of Region 20 is Isle of Man.
And then for 30, it's Japan and so on.
OK, so that was a lecture on some of the main analytical functions.
I hope you found it useful.