The ranking functions I want to talk about are row number, rank and rank row no returns, a unique
number for each row in your data.
The function takes no parameters and it numbers each row based on the order of the data.
Row number requires an order by clause within the clause if you're using Oracle, but you don't need
it for other database management systems such as MySQL, rank will rank your data within each partition.
It will assign the same rank for trade values and there can be gaps in the numbering.
For example, if two values are tied for second place, the next available ranking will be for.
And Frank will also rank your data with each politician, it will assign the same rank for tied values,
but this time there will not be gaps in the numbers.
For example, if two values are tied for second place, the next available number will be three.
To get the desired result for rank and then rank, you need to apply the order by clause in the over
clause for that field you would like to be ranked.
And again, if you're using our AS and you don't specify the order by clause for the rank and don'ts
rank functions, the query will fail.
Other the database management systems will still run.
But if you think about it, it doesn't really make sense to apply ranking functions without actually
ordering your data.
OK, so let's apply the three ranking functions to the countries table and order by population, so
select name population and I'll start with rule number
over quota by population.
Then I'll just copy this twice.
Change it to rank
and
tense rank underscore countries.
And the order by population is in ascending order by default if you don't specify ascending or descending.
Now, as you can see, the row number stops from one in increments, one for each year until we reach
two hundred and forty nine.
Which is the final word.
Now, let's look at rank and then rank, this is ranking the values based on population.
So the first two valleys, the first two rows have zero population and so are tied for number one.
But for the third row rank gives this a ranking of three and skips the number two.
Because if we had three rows tied for first, then it would skip three numbers and give the next rank
of four.
But if we look at Dennis rank, this gives the third row a rank of two and it doesn't skip a number.
And that's the difference between rank and Dennis rank.
OK, let's now apply a petition by the region ID to our query.
And also at the region, I'd call
and I will partitioned by the region, Heidi.
And I will add that.
To the other two functions.
And here.
So the same scenario applies as per the previous query.
But it is contained within the partition of each region.
So we in region and 10.
And the ranking starts again when we get to the next partition.
Now, just to show you, if I remove the order by clause and even one of the partitions.
We get Nera.
Missing order by expression in the window specification.
OK, so have some practice with these functions and apply different partitions so you can start to get
comfortable with them.