The distribution functions I want to talk about our present rank and Kim percent rank is the percentile
ranking of the number of a road between zero and one.
The formula is rank minus one, divided by the total number of rows, minus one.
And this is applied to each partition.
Kim, this is the cumulative distribution value within a group of values is the number of rose less
than or equal to the value of the current row, divided by the total number of rows.
And again, the value is between zero and one and applied to each partition.
To get the desired result, four percent rank and cume dysfunctions, you need to apply the order by
because inside the over clause for that field that you would like evaluated.
If you're using our escarole, the autobiographers is mandatory and the omission of an order by clause
will result in the query failure.
And again, another on another database management systems, the query remains to execute, but it will
not return any meaningful results because your data really needs to be ranked in order for this for
these functions to be meaningful.
OK, so let's apply the two distribution functions to the countries table and order it by population.
So we select name population percent rank over quarter by population.
And since we're ordering like population, that is what the percent rank function will evaluate, so
we will evaluate the population field and the same will go for the cume just function.
From EPA and school countries.
And here on.
Here are our results.
If I go right to the end.
Both the percent rank and the cume dysfunctions return one, which makes sense because the range is
between zero and one.
So now let's apply a partition by regionality.
Christianised it.
So the same scenario applies, except for the functions are applied to each participant, as you can
see, for the end of the partition for region and 10.
Both functions return one and then they start again at the next partition and again if I remove the
order by close.
We return an error.