OK, so for this scenario, what we'd like to do is find the difference between the country's population
in the current Roe vs. the population of the country with the highest population in the entire table.
So to do that, we take select name population.
And then use the emacs function.
On the population field over.
And we can just leave this blank because we'd like to find the max population for the entire table.
From EPA and school countries now, we still need to calculate the variance, but if I execute this
query, I just want to see what it looks like.
So we have a maximum population here, which is one point four billion, and I believe that's China.
And then we have the population for the country in the current rate.
So we just need to do this.
Were subtracted by this very.
To find the difference between the current country's population and the population of the country with
the maximal population, so that which is the population minus and I can just copy this analytical function
and that as diff from Max.
And you can see the population of Ireland is quite a lot lower than the population of China.