For this scenario, let's arrange our countries in order of population from largest, smallest and find
the difference between the population of the current country and the one after it.
So to do this, we can use the lead function, so let's select the country and the population for that
country and our analytical function.
So in the parameters, I would like population.
Because that is the field that I would like the lead function to pick up.
One, because that's the offset I would like one after the current, and that is the value by default.
So even if you leave it blank, it will be the same.
And individuals, I would just like to order my population sending from EPA and school countries.
Now, again, we haven't finished our query, but I just want to see what it looks like.
And as you can see.
The lead function brings the population of the country below the current rate.
And now what we need to do is subtract our analytical function to the population for the current role
to determine the variance, so copy into an equal amount to population minus the analytical function,
and I'll use that as variant.
So now we can see that the population of China is approximately six hundred and seventy million more
than the population of India and the population of India is approximately one billion more than the
population of the USA.