For this scenario, we want to flag a country that is in the top 10 percentile for its region, so to
do this, we can use percent rank.
We must order the population from highest to lowest and anything below or equal to zero point one,
which is the percent rank and is equivalent to the top 10 percentile because remember, percent rank
goes from zero to one.
She needs to be flagged.
So let's select a name which is the country name population, just so we have a reference of the population
for each country and then apply percent rank, we don't need to specify anything in the parameter,
four percent rank and in the over clause.
We must partition by region idea and order by population dissenting because we want from highest to
lowest for each partition.
And I'll select from Evea undisclosed countries now we have not finished the query, but I just want
to see what this looks like so far.
So now let me actually add regionality for clarity as well so we can see the partitions.
So for regionality 10, we can see that the partition we would like is up to Canada because after that
we get above zero point one.
So the top ten percentile countries in region 10 from the USA.
Up to Canada.
So we need to flag these as, let's say one and the rest is zero and the same as we go to the next partition
of 20.
This time we have the Russian Federation, Germany, UK, all the way up to Spain, which we'd like
to include.
So to do this, we can use a case statement that will keep this analytical function here just for reference,
and I'll copy it.
So I'll type case when.
And my condition, and I would like this less than or equal to zero point one dinoflagellates, one
else zero, and I'll end as top 10.
Acento.
You, Ron.
Now we have a flag for the top 10 percentile countries partitioned by each region.