For this scenario, let's order our countries by population in ascending order and create a running
total for the population which keeps adding on the next country's population as we go down to.
So what you need to do here is select the country's name.
Population and then use the some aggregation on population followed by the other groups.
Order by population ascending, just type AFSC, and that would be the default as well.
And then for hour window frame, we type Veronese between inbounded proceeding and current row.
And we'll call this a running total population from Epper underscore countries.
And let me just increase.
The road limit to five hundred.
And now we have the running total in the last column that is increasing as we go down each road and
adding on the population of the next country.
And as we get to the end, we have the total population of seven point seven billion.
I know that we could have just defined our window frame as Rose Inbounded proceeding, and it would
have given us the same result.