For the following assignment, questions will be using the customer orders data model specifically will
be creating a view that combines the orders table and the order items table.
Now, I'll show you how to create this view, so please make sure you're following along with the code
I'm about to run.
Otherwise, you'll not be able to do the assignment questions.
Now, I want to create a view that contains all the data from the orders table.
But what we're missing from the audit table is the total order value, and that information is in the
order items table.
So what we need at an older level is the unit price times the quantity to give us the total order value.
So what I want to do is join the orders table to the order items table and create a view from this joint,
but I can't just join the orders table to the order items table because the order I.D. is not unique
in the order items table.
So I'll need to group it before I can do the joint and I can group it on order.
So first for the query.
I'll select and leave, the column is blank for now, what I know is I want to select orders as I left
table.
I'll use that as a.
And it doesn't really matter what kind of joint I do, because I know that the order I.D. will match
on the orders table and the order items table, but I'll do a left joint, so left joint and this needs
to be on subquery.
So I'll select order ID and then the son of the unit price times quantity and I'll alias that.
As for the total from order items and group that I order, underscore it and is the sub query as B and
the joint will be done on a tall order, it equals B..
The order idee.
Now, one other thing to note is a very select staff from orders.
Is that I want the order status to be complete.
I do not want to include incomplete or refunded orders.
So a lot of vehicles here to say where a to order status equals and caps complete.
Now for the fields, I'd like all the fields here from the oldest table, so I'll type a star, use
a wild card and from the subquery, which I'm performing the joint on, all I really want is this order
total.
So let's run this query.
I know it's not been created as a verb yet.
Here is our results.
And as you can see, we've got the Oldroyd with the total for that order.
So now to create The View, I'll put this query in brackets.
And I'll write crazy and I'll call my veto orders as.
Terminate with the semicolon and execute this whole query that has been created.
If I go in to my object browser filter by these.
You should have a veto orders.
The.
OK, great.
So now we're ready to move on to the assignment questions, I've included a healthy number of these
because I believe the best way to master analytical functions is with practice.
So don't worry, if you find some of these questions difficult, review the solutions and make sure
you understand the logic.
And like I said, keep on practicing.