So to do this, we need to select the order idee.
The customer ready and we can use the rank function in our analytical function, partitioned by customer
ID and order
by order, total descending.
And the descending is very important because we want to order it from highest to lowest.
From our view, the underscore order's inherent.
So now we can see.
For each customer ID, so for customer ID one, we've got all their distinct orders.
And I should actually probably include order total so we can see what the actual order total is.
We can see it's a range from highest to lowest and then we start again as we get to the next customer
ID.
And again, to the next customer, Edy.