So to do this, we can use the two to function on the order date, time field, so let's just select
start from the orders first.
So as I was saying, we could use that to try to function on the order date time field to just extract
the month and the year.
So let me show you.
As you can see now, if you're not familiar with the two child function, I suggest you refer to the
documentation online and I've also covered it in my previous course, the comprehensive Esquibel course.
OK, so from our query, we can select voter ID.
To try to take time
out Ailey's this as a month.
Yeah, and I'd also like to order Total.
And to find the difference, I'd like to order total subtracted by the analytical function, utilizing
Max on the order total.
And I'd like that over the partition.
By the month and year combination.
Now, remember, I can't use the alias of Monsignor.
Because the select statement is executed after the window function.
Refer to the query order of execution if you're unfamiliar with this, so now I'll aliased this as diff
from Max from the underscore orders and here.
So now for the month of January 2021, we can see that the order total in the current row of one hundred
one point seven.
Is two hundred and ninety eight point thirty three less than the maximum order total?
And if I scroll down.
While we're still in the position of January twenty one.
We can see that here the variance is zero.
So four hundred point zero three is our maximum order total.
And as we get to the next partition.
Which is February twenty one, again, we can see that on maximum order total is five one seven point
six nine, and that is where the variance is taken from.