So for this question, we need to first define a window frame using ranges and order or data based on
month and year.
So we can use the to try to function again to get the month in year combination, but we cannot apply
this to arrange range window frame because ranges do not accept characters.
So we can be a bit creative here and convert or to CHA output to a no output and use a format mask that
suits this requirement.
So let me show you so I'll select order date time from the borders.
Now I can use that to try to convert this order the daytime into four digit year and a month combination.
And will this although this looks like in America after the trial function and choose, it's a character
out there so I can then use the two number function to convert this to a number?
And now we can apply a range window frame, we're using ranges instead of rows because we're interested
in the entire value for the current month and year.
So when we're on September of 2020, we want to calculate the total for September 2020 as this group.
And if we subtract one from this, it will be.
August of twenty twenty.
Whereas if we were to use Rose, we would only be doing this at every level, so ranges suit our requirements.
So the following month is one unit higher and the previous month is one unit lower.
Great.
So let's start populating our query.
I would like to order it and I'm just going to copy this and for output I'll leave.
This is to try and convert this to a month in year combination for readability.
And I'll also get the order total and now for our window function, I'd like to use the average segregation
on the order total over partition.
By.
Would the date time in the year and month former?
Order by the same.
And use the range as to proceed.
This is the same as saying range between two preceding and current road.
And I'll use this as average three months.
And now I can take the order total and subtract that.
From this window function.
An 80s that has variants.
And here, Ron.
So now you can see that the average three months for March of twenty twenty is one hundred and sixty
four point seven.
And the variance in the current rose context is thirty four point seven, and that will continue.
As we go down to the next valley, which is April 20, 20, and that will take the rolling average,
and because we've only got one month previous to that, that will be the rolling average of March and
April.
So this question was a little bit trickier, and we had to be a bit creative in terms of getting our
out.
This isn't the only way to get the result.
This is just one of the ways.
And if you find a more creative way, then that's also fine.