When performing a normal group, you return the summary rose based on the group columns, but you do
not return any subtotal or grand totals, as you can see on the example table, on the slide.
Using Tube Roll-Up and grouping sets, which are known as extensions to the group by Bangalore's, can
allow you to obtain subtitles and grand totals in your group by results.
And you can see this on the right side table.
We now have two rows which contain the subtitles based on the location it.
So the total for location one is two hundred thousand and location two is one hundred thousand.
We also return a grand total, which is three hundred thousand.
So in the course of the next few lectures, I will talk about the various extensions to the group by
clause so that you can return subtitles and grandnephew tools in your group by queries.