Roll-Up is an extension to the group bylaws that allows you to generate subtotal as well as mine totals.
The subtitles are generated based on the order of the columns provided after the Roll-Up Keywood, the
first column provided is on the top of the hierarchy and the last column provided is at the bottom of
the hierarchy.
So in the syntax on the screen, we have to non-segregated columns in our select statement, column
one and column two in our group because we have the Roll-Up extension with column one and column two
in parenthesis.
Column one is first.
So that is greater than column two in terms of its hierarchy.
So when the subtitles are generated, they are done first for the column one column two combination
and then it's done for the column one combination on its own.
And then finally it's done for the grand total.
In the next example, we have three columns in the roll up extension column.
One is greater than column two and column two is greater than column three in terms of its hierarchy.
And this is based on the ordering column one is first column to a second and column three third.
So that's also the order of the hierarchy.
So when the subtotal is generated first, they are generated for column one, two and three and then
they are generated for column one and column two combination and then calculated for the column one
on its own.
And then the grand total is calculated.
OK, so let's do an example, using our eBay underscore countries table, I first want to do a group
buy and return the total population grouped by region and subregion.
I note that I will use the Engvall function to replace null values for the region.
Idee and subregion ID columns to replace nulls with zero as nodes can be confusing to interpret when
analysing our results.
So I type select and then I specify Engvall region underscore.
And zero zero is the value to replace and he knows that Engvall sub region and then the aggregation,
which will be the sum of the population.
From India on the scale countries, and I want to groove by these two points and note, I am retaining
the enviable evening in the group columns and here by.
Here are our results.
No, we don't have any.
Subtotal or grand hotels, apart from obviously the totals of the region, idee and subregion it grew
by.
So now let's use the Roll-Up in our group by clause, so I will.
Type Roll-Up.
Open parenthesis, put this in a single line for readability, close parentheses and terminate with
a semicolon.
And here, run.
So before I even evaluate the results, I'll tell you what I expect to see, I would expect to see some
totals for the region and the subregions combination, which would also be returned by the normal group,
by Claw's anyway.
So no change there.
But then I would also expect to see the region totals as the subregion.
It would get dropped off and then I would expect to see the grand total.
So as you can see.
All of these rows here are the combinations for regionality and subregion anyway, and then where we've
got a nul in the subregion, it signifies that we've got a total value for regionality.
So you can see that the value for regionality 10 is just over a billion, and that would be the sum
of these two values here.
And if we keep scrolling down.
Where we've got to null values would be the grand total.
So that would be seven point seven billion.
OK, great.
So next, let's do a roll up with three columns, let's add organization regionality.
So I will type Engvall organization region wide.
Papilla, don't forget to do a comma before and then add that to the hierarchy.
And he and actually, before I hit run this time, what I expect to see would be the subtitles for the
region in the subregion was an organization regionality, as you would even if this was a group by statement.
Then I would expect to see the subtotal for the region and the subregion I'd combination and then just
for the region it and then the grand total, so let's it run.
So as you can see.
Each row individually is showing the combination of all three columns, and then we have the total for
the region and the sub region and combinations where we have no value in the third column.
And then where we have another value in the subregion, it and the organization region IT fields would
be the total for the region.
So this is the total for region wide 10, which is, again, just over one billion.
And then if I keep scrolling down.
We have the grand total where all columns are No.
You also don't need to include all columns in your roll up, you can do a partial roll up, but of course
you do need to have all non-segregated columns from your select statement in the group by at least,
otherwise you'll get an error.
So let's remove organization regionalised from the Roll-Up extension and just put it as a group by.
So this is known as a partial Roll-Up and the grouping for region, subregion, ID and organization
region ID will still happen, but then the Roll-Up will happen for the region and the subregion.
It.
First, it will evaluate the subtotal for the region and the sub region, it along with the organization
Region Idee.
Then it will calculate the subtotal for the region, it along with the organization region, and then
it will calculate the subtotal for organization region on its own because that is outside the ruler.
So it will always be in a subtotal combination.
And as you can see, we return combinations of all three.
And then the combination of the region and the organization region in.
And then the total for the organization region it only and we don't return the grand total because no
matter what happens, we must group by organization regionality, which is outside of the Roll-Up.
Now, if I was to remove the organization regionality altogether.
I would get an error.
Because we still need to group this non-segregated field.
OK, so these examples are just to show you the different ways that you can leverage the role up extension
in your group because.