Cube is an extension to the group by clause that allows you to generate subtitles as well as granting
tools just like Roll-Up.
However, the subtitles are generated based on all combinations of the provided columns in the Cube
extension parenthesis, there is no hierarchy unlike the Roll-Up extension.
So in the Syntex on the screen, we again have to non-segregated columns in our select statement, column
one and column two in our group because we have the cube extension with column one and column two in
parenthesis.
The subtitles will happen for column one and column two as a combination column one on its own.
Column two on its own and in the grand total, to win the column one or column two, limiting the total
calculation.
In the next example, we have three columns in the Cube extension, so now we have eight possible combinations.
So unlike the Roll-Up, where it's done based on a hierarchy, the cube extension will generate subtitles
for all possible combinations.
OK, so let's do an example using our eBay underscore pantry's table again.
Let's do the same previs example we did with Roll-Up where we used regionality and subregion EITE.
But this time we'll use the cube extension rather than the rolled up extension.
So I'm going to select and we'll regionality zero and we'll sub region wide zero sum of the population
as the aggregation from eBay and school countries.
By this time I'll type KUB.
And I will copy this.
Into the parenthesis for Cube, put into a single line for readability.
Terminating the semicolon.
InterOil.
So before I review this, what I expect to see would be the subtitles for the region, Idy and the subregion
I'd combination, and then for region regionality on its own and then for subregion, it is on its own
and in the Grand Hotel.
So as you can see, we first have the Grand Hotel where we've got nulls for the region and the subregion,
and we then have the totals for the subregion as they were nulls in the region ID field.
So this is the subtotal for subregion ID 10.
This is the subtotal for some reason, ID 20 and so on.
And then as I scroll down where we have Noles in the subregion, I'd feel it would be the total for
the region it.
So this is the total for region, I'd tell, which is, again, just over just over a billion.
And then this would be the total for region wide 20.
And where we have a region under subregion it populated, that will be the combination of region and
subregion it which would have occurred in a normal group by statement anyway.
So as you can see, unlike roller cube evaluates all combinations, if I was to change this to a up
right now, we would no longer be able to see the total for subregion.
It, as I'm about to show you.
As you can see, we no longer have the total just for the subregion it.
And that is because that gets dropped off as it's lower in the hierarchy, whereas with Cuba, all of
the combinations are evaluated.
As you can see, we now have subregion in total again.
Now, as with the roll up extension, you can also do a partial cube where you have some non-segregated
columns in the group by close but not in the cube extension.
It works pretty much as you'd expect after seeing the example on the role of lecture.
So I won't go over that again, but I'll leave you to investigate that in your own time.