OK, so I just wanted to clarify quickly why I'm using the Anvil formula in my queries.
So let's evaluate the EPA on this whole country's table and group by the region and subregion to get
the total population.
And here on.
Now, as I interpret the results, you can see that there is a small population of one one two six belonging
to Region 40, but it does not have a subregion ID and it's populated in not.
Now, let's see what happens when I apply a roll of extension on this query.
We seem to return a peculiar result at Regenhard, 40, we seem to have two subtitles for Regenhard.
Forty one with a population of around 42 million.
And one with just one one two six, but you recall, this is the same number as the sub region that
was populated with a known value.
So when you're actually trying to evaluate this, it actually looks pretty confusing.
It appears that this is the subtotal for regionality, 40, but it's not this is actually just the total
for region 40 with a sub region.
It is.
No, and that's different.
And hence why this field is causing confusion.
Now, if I replace the null value in the sub region ID field with a zero instead by using the Engvall
formula.
Then it will become clearer.
So if I apply and Val.
To the subregion, it field.
And now he run.
The null has been replaced with a zero, and now it actually becomes clearer to see here is the subtotal
and here is actually the valley where the region is 40.
But the sub region, it was previously no.
It's now been replaced with a zero.
And that is why I'm using Engvall in my columns to remove these null values as they contradict what
the subtotal columns are trying to show.