The grouping ID function provides a flag for the specific subtotal or grand total that has been shown
at the root level based on your group by extension.
It can be used in the select statement only when a group, by extension has been used, the same columns
that are included in your group, by extension, should be enclosed in the grouping ID functions parentheses
to an example of the syntax is shown on the screen.
And as you can see, we've applied a roll up on column one and column two and the grouping, it also
contains column one and column two in its parentheses.
OK, so let's say we have two columns as per the previous Syntex show.
Well, how would the grouping flag these?
Well, it would do it for every combination.
So if the group ID field return zero, then all provided columns have been grouped.
If it returns, one in the first column has been subtitled, if it returns to and the second column
has been subtitled.
If it returns three, then this is the grand total.
Note that if we have three columns, we would have eight combinations, and so the group would go up
to seven for the grand total as it starts with zero and the grand total will always get the highest
number.
OK, so let's run our query again, where we roll up by region and subregion it and this time had the
group in it too.
So I will select and Vale region, Heidi, and the southern region, Heidi, and then I will add the
grouping ID with both of these columns inside of it.
Close parentheses and then get the some of the population from Libya and Isco countries and group by
Roll-Up.
And at.
They say as well, terminate with a semi-trailer until around.
So before I evaluate this fully, because we're doing a roll up, as I mentioned previously, I expect
to see the flags at zero one and three because we would not have subregion.
I'd subtotal on it, so.
And as you can see.
That is the case, we only see zero one and three one is where we got the region it total and three
is the grand total.
OK, so let's change this to Cube now.
And this time, I would expect to see zero one, two and three as the group it likes and that is the
case.
Three is the grand total, two is the subregion total one, as we've seen previously in the region,
it total rose.
And zero would just be.
The region and subregion, it combination's.
Now, if I had a third column that's non-segregated, such as organization regionality, and then add
that to the grouping it and the cube extension, then I expect my grouping ID to go all the way up to
seven because with three columns there are eight possible combinations.
And since the group it starts with zero, I'd expect the grand total to be flagged as number seven.
So let's test that.
Had to cut my hair and then at that.
Antipas grouping idee.
As well as the cube function.
So now when I hit run.
We can see that the grouping is for the grand total is seven.
And if I change this to roll up, I would expect to see a lot of blank numbers, but I would still expect.
The grand total to be up to seven, because the grouping, it will always number everything based on
every possible combination, even though the Roll-Up evaluates the subtitles based on the hierarchy.
And as you can see.
We have a lot of gaps in our numbering, but when we get down to the grand total, it's still seven.