Instead of using Roll-Up or Cube, you can specify your own grouping set.
So, for example, if we wanted to return subtitles for column one and column two together and then
only for column two, we can specify that in the groupings that as per the slide.
Each grouping must be separated with a comma and multiple column groupings should be enclosed in parenthesis.
So in the next example, we have three groupings, column three and column two or one, grouping column
two and column one is another grouping and column one is a grouping on its own.
So they are generated subtitles.
OK, so let's do a grouping set for subtitles with regionality subregion and óg regionality only, but
not the other combinations such as Çok regionality, an organization region together.
If we use a rollup or a cube, we would get the subtitles that we don't want and sometimes you want
to customize the groupings.
So this is a perfect example to use grouping sets.
So I would type select.
Feel for region, Heidi.
And feel free sub region, Heidi.
And Bill, for her organization, regionality.
The aggregation, we should be the sum of population from undisclosed countries, and then I want to
gloopy the grouping set and this will be whatever I specify I want it to be for the combination of three,
these three just on their own.
So I limpert that into the parameters.
So each individual one will be treated as their own grouping.
So only the combinations listed here will get generated subtitles.
So let's get right.
Now, as you can see, we've got the total.
For region wide, the total for subregion is.
And the total for organization regionality, if I won grand totals to, then I can add that to the end
of the list here by just doing open and close parentheses and here run.
And now we also return the grand total and like I said, you can also combine columns.
So if I wanted the total region in the subregion, I'd combination to.
And then the ÓG region, it has another combination on its own.
I can then modify the query.
To be like this, I'll have regionality.
And subregion ID in parentheses, I'll have organization regionality on its own.
And then I will get rid of the open and close parenthesis
so that we don't calculate the grand to.
And yet ran.
So now we can see that we've got the combination for region wide and subregion where organization region
it is now and then we've got the combination for organization, region it on its own to.
And we only get to grouping's because that's all we specified.
And again, I can add the grand total.
And then we get back to at the end.
No, that, as with all group by requirements, all non-segregated columns in the select statement must
be in the group by all the group by extension.
So if I remove organization, region it.
And yet, Ron.
We get an error, but if I copy this outside of the grouping set and it run.
The query works fine, so that's just one thing to be aware of.