You can put multiple columns in parenthesis in your cube and roll up extensions, and they will be treated
as composite columns, meaning they will be evaluated like the single columns.
So in the syntax on the left, we have three columns individually specified in the roll up extension.
They get evaluated in hierarchy order as per normal.
But in the syntax on the right, we have column one and column two in parentheses, so they both treated
as a single column.
Column one and column two are evaluated along with column three as per before, but in the next level,
column one and column two are evaluated.
But after that, rather than having column to drop off, we lose both column one and column two and
get to the grand total.
This is an example of composite columns in your roll up and cube extensions.
If you provide multiple columns in parentheses, they will get treated like they are single columns.
So in this instance, column one and column two are being treated as a single column and they will not
be evaluated individually.