OK, so for this question, we just need to group by subregion and óg regionality.
We need a Roll-Up extension and to provide subregion as the top level hierarchy and then all Guijin
after this way, it will evaluate the subregion and all region total as per the usual group gloopy,
and then the subregion indeed as the top hierarchy.
And then it will also calculate the grand total.
Another requirement was to not have any null values, so we will use NPL with our subregion and ÓG region,
it fields in both the select statement and the by extension clauses and populate nulls with zero.
So for our solution, we type select the sub region idee zero and organization region wide.
Ziva.
Some of population as the aggregation from EPA and school countries, we group by the Roll-Up.
And then copying our two fields.
Subregion, it should be first, as that is the top hierarchy and then organization regionality should
be second.
And here are the results.
We have the usual subregion ID and organization regionality totals, which would be captured in the
usual group by clothes anyway without any extensions.
Then we have the totals for the subregion with the organization region it is now.
And then we have the grand total.