OK, so for this question, we just need to have our subtitles for all combinations of the non-segregated
fields'.
So we can use Cube instead of Roll-Up.
And another requirement was to not have any no values, so we'll use the envy formula again.
And on top of that, we need to show the grouping it this time, so we will use the grouping IT formula
and have the subregion ID and all region it inside it.
So we type select in the sub region wide,
the organization region wide.
And then the group ID formula, which will take.
These two columns in.
But then in the same line.
It is this group, Heidi, and then the aggregation, which is population from undisclosed countries.
We then would find the cube extension.
And I can actually just copy this.
Into that cube extension.
And here.
And here are our results.
And we can see from the flag.
That here is a subtotal with the group of three.
Group 82 is the organization regionalised, Total Group 81 is the subregion in total, and Group Zero
is the usual subregion and organization regionality subtitles.