OK, so for this example, we can use grouping sets as we have a specified grouping requirement.
And we must also use Engvall to replace Norns with zero when it comes to the region and subregion,
it feels.
So we type, select and deal for region wide zero.
And the sub region wide zero and the organization reaching 80 zero.
And then the aggregation, which is some of the population.
From the debate from the school countries, and then we regrouped by.
Grouping sets open parenthesis, and now I'll leave some gaps here so that I can ensure that I've put
this in properly and for the first grouping, I would like regionality and organization regionality.
So I'll just copy all of this in here and I'll format it inside the parentheses.
Get rid of subregions it.
So here's the first grouping.
I'll put that in the same line and I'll give it its own parenthesis.
Close parenthesis here for the next grouping.
I would like subregion ID, an organization, region ID.
How is that?
Get rid of the comma and then terminate with a semicolon.
So here is our greeting sets.
We've got regionality and organization REGENHARD and then we've got subregion ID and organization regionality.
And remember to use Northville even in the group clothes and run.
OK, so we can now see the total.
For the region and the region, it as well as.
The subregion ID and the old regionality.