I want to talk about two functions that can handle null values in your data sets, we'll be using these
functions throughout the course and being able to handle no values is very important.
Coalesce takes two or more expressions, and for each role, it returns the first value from these expressions
that is not null.
So let's say you have two problems, first name and nickname, sometimes you find that the first name
is left blank and when it's left blank, usually it's because the first name is in the nickname fueled
by accident.
You can create a column using coalesce to return the first name, if it is not null, otherwise return
the nickname if the first name is no.
So as you can imagine, the ordering is important as it will take the value from the first expression
that is not null.
If all of the expressions are no, then it will return all the data types in each expression must also
be the same.
You can't have a numerical data type in the first expression and a character to type in the next.
The syntax for coalesce is to have coalesce, open parenthesis and list all of the expressions you'd
like to include.
OK, so let's query our table.
I want to column that will return either the Web address first.
And if there is no Web address, then return the story.
So I can type.
Select name, web address and then coalesce and the first expression, because, remember, ordering
is important is Web address and then if that's no, then provide the store name and hit run.
As you can see in the first row, we have the Web address, the remaining rows for the Web address on
now.
So the story has been populated instead.
So let's see what happens if I swap the expressions around and I have stoning first.
Now, basically, we return all the store names in the store name field, including online rather than
the Web address.
So this is just a reminder that the ordering is important, store name is prioritized because it's first
and since then has no null values.
The Web address field is not used at all.
OK, so let's now add another expression storewide.
Now, this time we get an error because storewide is a numeric data type.
So we must ensure that all of the expressions are of the same data type.
Never takes no values from an expression and replaces it with a specified strain.
So, for example, if you wanted all no values to be zero, instead, you can do that.
If the expression in the first parameter is a character, then it converts the replacement stream to
a character.
If it's numeric, then it's a bit more complicated, but usually convert it into a numeric data type.
So here's the syntax for Engvall.
It takes an expression which is usually a field, and then you type your replacement string.
OK, so let's clear we are on the table.
In the cornfield, we have notes for commissions for many employees, let's replace these novels with
zero.
So I will alias the asterisk and then I'll do Annville com, which is the field and then the replacement,
which is zero for unknown values.
And here.
And now, as you can see in our field, we have zeros instead of the normal values.
Now, let's try to replace this with the string no commission.
We get an error as it must be the same data type uncombed only takes numeric values.
So we can replace strength with character data types and the string must be enclosed in single words,
if we do so, let me select Star from Impaction.
And now what I'll do is I'll insert a record into the table and I'll leave the E name has no.
So I will type insert into AMP.
Valli's.
Zero techno, no.
Which is a test for the job manager, right?
Zero system with Heidi, thousand for the salary, no for the commission and 10 for the Depner and.
OK, so now a redemptive looking.
And at this time, I want to replace I want to use the anvil function on the Inamed field, unpopulated,
with no name instead of any no values.
So I can type select your name and feel your name.
And now this time I enclose in single vote because I'm entering a string and I'll take no name.
And as you can see, we have no name instead.
So now let me just delete the record I inserted.
There we go.