Training enables you to remove leading and trailing characters such as whitespace from character strength.
The syntax is to type trem open parentheses, you then have the option to specify leading, which is
the start of the string trading, which is the end of the string or both, which is leading and trading.
The default is both if left blank.
So this is where it searches for your trim source.
The trim character is the character or characters to remove from your string.
So if you specify leading followed by lowercase s character, it will remove any lowercase S's at the
start of your string.
You then type from followed by the Transource characters should be enclosed in single quotes and the
default trim character is a white space.
This function is particularly useful if you want to remove trailing or leading white space.
OK, so let's query the table.
Let's say I wanted to remove the first letter of each employee that starts with K.
I can type select his name just so we can have that there was a reference to the letter K..
From his name.
So this is the Trem character and this is the dream source I haven't specified, leading or trailing,
so by default it's both.
And let's hear from.
And now King becomes a.
So let's use the dual table for some more examples.
Let's say I have a string with white space at the start and at the end of it, if I want to remove it,
I can type.
The white space has the trim character from and this is the actual trim source.
And now when I hit run.
We return white space with no white space, and I can make this even clearer by checking the length
of the.
So at prison, the length is ten characters.
And that is because he has removed leading and trailing whitespace, if I specify leading.
Then the length is 13, that is because it two.
Characters at the Star, which are white space, and they get removed, and in the end we have three
white space characters, so three plus the 10 four white space equals 13.
If I change this to trailing.
We get 12 because we remove the three white space characters at the end.
But retain the tube at the front.
Let's say you wanted to ensure all values in your field were of the same length will, you could put
them with characters to ensure that they are of the same length.
If the added value is below the required length, it will get padded either on the left or the right
side with the character that you specify.
If it exceeds the required length, then it gets truncated from either the left or the right side.
Both iPad and iPad take three expressions, the field with the values.
The length that the value should be after padding and the Pat character.
OK, so let's query the table.
Let's say I want the emperor to be five characters and it should have leadings, even if the emperor
does not have the required length of life I can select.
But because I want to pad on the left side.
The field, which is the length, which is five and the Pat character, which is over.
And he writes.
And now the empire is five characters.
Now, what if I want?
The job field to be a maximum six characters, if it's less than six characters and padded with a capital
X on the right side.
So what I can do is select Chaubey for comparison and then I go to Arpad.
The field, which is the length, which is six and the character X and.
So now where the original field exceeds six characters, it gets truncated and where it's below six
characters like Clerck, it gets padded with a capital X.
Now for the final example.
So let's say the salary field is in thousands and I want to add three zeros to the end.
I can just type Arpad cell and for the length I can specify the length of the Southy field plus three,
because whatever the length is, I want to add three to the end of it, followed by zero.
And now we have to value with three zeros added at the end of each of it.
OK, so that was showing you how to use trim and pad.