The greatest and least functions take a list of expressions and return either the lowest or highest
value from that list.
This can be useful if you want to cap a salary, for example, no one should earn less than five hundred
or higher than three thousand.
The first expression in that list is used to determine the date to type.
The syntax for greatest and least is to put in a list of expressions inside the parentheses.
OK, so let's query the table.
So I want to call them that does not allow the salary to be higher than three thousand.
And if it is, then it cuts it to that value of three thousand so I can select.
All the fields from the table, followed by the least function in my list, Putzel and three thousand.
And as you can see, the lowest value out of the salary of three thousand has been displayed in each
room and in this instance, three thousand is lower than five thousand.
So it's been displayed.
Now, what if nobody should be paid less than one thousand more than I can change this to the greatest
and this to be one thousand?
So now the higher of salary or 1000 will be populated.
And now Smith has a salary of one thousand rather than eight hundred.