Pivot allows you to transpose Roe values into columns.
The syntax is quite complicated to look at first, but it becomes familiar with practice in your pre
pivot table.
You essentially have columns of interest.
One column will contain the field you want to aggregate, along with the column that contains the values
you want to convert into columns.
So, for example, if you have a job column with Manager Plurk and President and values, it will convert
these values into their own columns.
In the pivot line, in the bottom you type pivot, followed by parentheses, you start with the aggregation
function.
Then type four, followed by the column, you want to pivot.
You then type.
In followed by the list of values in that column, inside parentheses, note that you cannot use a sub
query to generate that list.
It has to be typed in and finally right at the top.
We type select stock as this selects the pivoted columns.
OK.
So let's do an example, let me query the EPA under article countries table.
Now, what if I wanted a matrix of values showing me subregion along the roads and regionality along
the columns?
With the population totals as the values.
Well, we can use Pivot to do this.
So I can start by typing Select Star from and that is my top level select statement and in the first
parenthesis we type select followed by the columns of interest.
We would one region and subregion ID, as we need these for our Matrix film, and we also want to aggregate
the population field, so we want population to and it's from the EPA underscore countries table.
We now type in our pivot clothes.
Followed by the aggregation, which is the sum of population, and we're doing this for the region idee.
We then type in and type in the list of values in the region and field as they will be turned.
Intercoms.
You can do this by typing select distinct region, Heidi, from eBay and countries, and we will now
see a list of the values.
And there's only five.
So in my list, I can take 10, 20, 30, 40, 50 and terminate with a semicolon and note, I would
have to include these in single quotes if they were character strings.
So let's it run.
OK, great.
So here's our matrix, and we can see that region 30 has a population of just over seven hundred million
for subregions.
One hundred and ten.
And around about one point nine billion for for subregion and 30.
So we now have a Matrix V.
And just to note that we chose the aggregation field to be population.
We can also choose it to be number of countries.
And if that's the case, we don't even need the population field.
We can actually just account for the region wide field.
And if I hit run again.
We now have the number of countries in The Matrix.
So there are five countries for regionality, 30 and subregion.
One hundred and ten and nine for region 30 and subregion 30.
So that was just a lecture showing you how to pivot your data.