Pivot transforms columns into rows.
This will create two new columns, one column will contain the previous column names which you can use
and another will contain the aggregated values from the pivot view.
The syntax for unbefitting a table is to first select all columns from the pivot table.
You then type on pivo and open parentheses.
You went to the name that you would like to give, the column that holds the measures.
This is a new column that will be created, followed by the full keyword and the name of the column
that you want to hold the existing pivoted column names.
This will hold these values his record.
You then type in and list out each of the column names.
You can aliased them to that select star from table at the top, as I mentioned, will just select the
unpiloted table.
OK, so let's give an example, I'm going to create a table.
And it will contain the average test scores for three classrooms across three subjects maths, science
and English.
So the first problem will be class and it will be a virtual 10 day to time.
The second column will be called Maths, and it will be another day to type.
The third column will be science and it will be a no later time.
And the fourth column will be English and it will be a no later type.
And now I will insert values
into this into the table.
So for the first class will be seven a.
And the schools will be 70, 50, 80, and I will enter that, I will copy that three times.
I will change this to be 70 and 70.
And the scores will be 80, 80, 90, 70, 80, let's say 67.
And 89 and I will insert these three values.
Values keyword here.
And I'll insert these three into the table.
OK, so let's query a table.
So we have the three classrooms.
And the average results in maths, science and English, so this is a matrix.
Well, what if instead I wanted to transform this so that the data for test scores and subject were
in two columns?
One column showing the subject and another showing the average school voter on Pivot the table, we
can type select stuff from average test scores.
And then on Pivot.
So first, we type the name for the field containing our measure, which is called our average school.
Followed by the 40 foot.
And then the column that holds the values, math, science and English, we can call that subject,
we type in keyword and now we can type the column names math, science and English in a list for the
Jader and Germany.
And I once I hit run.
We have our data on pivoted.
We can also aliased these records so I can change formats as mathematics and.
And now that has changed as mathematics.