OK, so before we actually write our pivot query, let's check the distinctive values in the job column
as that's the column we're pivoting.
So the distinctive values are analyst, clerck, salesman, manager and president.
OK, so now let's build our query.
So we select staff from and then in our first select statement inside the parentheses, we're interested
in the depth field.
Job and sell the debt and job will form the rows and columns of our matrix and the cell will be aggregated
from the table.
We then type pivot.
Well, aggregation is the sum of cell four and then the field, which we're pivoting, which is job,
we specify the keyword and then list out the values in the job column.
We do this in single quotes because it's character data type analyst,
Plurk
salesman, manager.
And president.
And hit one.
And here is our result.