So first off, run the Esquibel command to prepare for this assignment, so run them one at a time.
So first I'll create the table.
Then I will insert each record.
Into the table.
So now I'll query the table.
So from the solution, we can see that we want the column holding the number of goals to be called goals
and the column holding the years to be called season, and it also appears that the season and values
have been aliased.
So year twenty eighteen is aliased to twenty eighteen.
To take one pill at this table, we type until after the next afternoon goes preseason.
And we had goals as the name of the column that contains the aggregated measure.
For.
And then season is the name of the new column that holds the existing column names in and then we write
here twenty eighteen as twenty eighteen year and school twenty nineteen has twenty nineteen.
Yeah, twenty twenty has twenty twenty.
And here, right?
And here are our results, uninhibited.